Henry Y. Porter Theater Memorabilia Collection MS003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Scrapbooks, playbills and programs, opera and theatrical personalities and performances, 1815 -- 1982; 1900 -- 1960; MS003.003; 6.9 Linear Feet
  - Picturesque Composition Book, scrapbook of actors and their famous roles, 1904; MS003.003.121.00001 (Box 121)
    Handwritten notes by each picture about the famous roles that actors such as Viola Allan, Otis Skinner, Leslie Carter etc. played. This scrapbook is not in Porter's handwriting.
  - Edith Helena in Lucia di Lammermoor, and loose clippings, circa 1910 -- 1916; 1955; MS003.001265 (Box 122)
- Obituary scrapbooks of musical, opera, theatrical and political figures, 1854 -- 1979; 1940 -- 1960; MS003.004; 10.9 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes
  This series contains bound series of obituary scrapbooks ranging from musicians, singers, actors and actresses, American, WWI and WWII personalities. There is also a Boston Symphony Orchestra scrapbook of the same binding included in the series.
  This series is arranged by obituary type.
  - Literary Obituaries, 1940 -- 1949; MS003.004.069.00001 (Box 69)
    Obituary scrapbook.
  - Musical Obituaries, 1907 -- 1951; MS003.004.070.00001 (Box 70)
    Obituaries and clippings.
  - Musical Obituaries Volume II, 1954 -- 1957; MS003.004.071.00001 (Box 71)
  - Musical Obituaries Volume III, 1957 -- 1960; MS003.004.072.00001 (Box 72)
  - Musical Obituaries Volume IV, 1960 -- 1963; MS003.004.073.00001 (Box 73)
  - Musical Obituaries, Volume V, 1963 -- 1967; MS003.004.074.00001 (Box 74)
  - Musical Obituaries Volume VI, 1967 -- 1969; MS003.004.075.00001 (Box 75)
  - Music miscellaneous, 1854 -- 1950; MS003.004.076.00001 (Box 76)
    Obituaries and clippings of opera singers and musical personalities.
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1917 -- 1918; MS003.004.077.00001 (Box 77)
    Clippings on Dr. Karl Muck.
  - Theatre Obituaries, 1938 -- 1949; MS003.004.078.00001 (Box 78)
  - Theatre Obituaries Volume II, 1950 -- 1953; MS003.004.079.00001 (Box 79)
  - Theatre Obituaries Volume III, 1953 -- 1956; MS003.004.080.00001 (Box 80)
  - Theatre Obituaries Volume IV, 1956 -- 1959; MS003.004.081.00001 (Box 81)
  - Theatre Obituaries Volume V, 1959 -- 1960; MS003.004.082.00001 (Box 82)
  - Theatre Obituaries Volume VI, 1960 -- 1961; MS003.004.083.00001 (Box 83)
  - American Obituaries, 1936 -- 1955; MS003.004.084.00001 (Box 84)
    Obituaries and clippings of politicians and American figures.
  - American Obituaries Volume II, 1930 -- 1953; MS003.004.085.00001 (Box 85)
  - Otis Emerson Dunham, 1876 -- 1950; MS003.004.086.00001 (Box 86)
  - World War I Obituaries, 1933 -- 1967; MS003.004.087.00001 (Box 87)
    Obituaries and clipping of WWI figures.
  - World War II Obituaries, 1941 -- 1979; MS003.004.088.00001 (Box 88)
    Obituaries and clippings of WWII figures.
  - Obituaries, circa 1921 -- 1928; MS003.001262 (Box 122)
  - Obituaries, circa 1926 -- 1936; MS003.001263 (Box 122)
  - Obituaries, circa 1943 -- 1947; MS003.001264 (Box 122)
- Phonograph records, 1937 -- 1947; MS003.005; 1 Volumes
  This series contains 78 RPM recordings. Includes some notes from the album covers and an original leaflet from the Scarlatti album. Includes Madrigals and other selected works by Monteverdi on the HMV label, Fourteen Sonatas for Harpsichord by Scarlatti on the Columbia label and the Dumbarton Oaks Concerto on the Keynote label and Symphonie de Psaumes on the Columbia label both by Stravinsky.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by composer.
  - Monteverdi Madrigals and other selected works; Il Ballo dell'ingrate, 1937 -- 1938; MS003.005.106.00001 (Box 106)
    On the HMV label. Arranged by Nadia Boulanger.
  - Monteverdi Madrigals and other selected works; A. Hor ch'el ciel e la Terra; B. Ecco Mormorar l'onde, 1937 -- 1938; MS003.005.106.00002 (Box 106)
    On the RCA Victor label. Arranged and conducted by Nadia Boulanger. Recorded in Paris Feb. 11, 13, 17, 1937.
  - Monteverdi Madrigals and other selected works; A. Hor ch'el ciel e la Terra concluded B. Amor (Lamento della Ninfa), 1937 -- 1938; MS003.005.106.00003 (Box 106)
  - Monteverdi Madrigals and other selected works; Zefiro Torna, 1937 -- 1938; MS003.005.106.00004 (Box 106)
    On the HMV label. Arranged by Nadia Boulanger. Date is approximate
  - Monteverdi Madrigals and other selected works; A: Ardo; B: 1)Ohime dove il mio ben 2)Chiame d'oro, 1937 -- 1938; MS003.005.106.00005 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 107 in D major and No. 384 in F major, 1937; MS003.005.106.00006 (Box 106)
    Columbia label, Masterworks set no. 298. Harpsichord played by Yella Pessl.
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 108 in D major and No. 218 in C major, 1937; MS003.005.106.00007 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 129 in G major and No. 33 in B minor, 1937; MS003.005.106.00008 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 58 in D minor, No. 238 in A major and No. 327 on B flat major, 1937; MS003.005.106.00009 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 243 in A minor, No. 490 in G major and No. 434 in B flat major, 1937; MS003.005.106.00010 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord; No. 205 in C major and No. 407 in C minor, 1937; MS003.005.106.00011 (Box 106)
  - Scarlatti - Fourteen sonatas for harpsichord, leaflet, 1937; MS003.005.106.00012 (Box 106)
    Letter to a music lover by Yella Pessl.
  - Igor Stravinsky - Dumbarton Oaks concerto; parts 1 and 4, 1947; MS003.005.106.00013 (Box 106)
    On the Keynote label. Recorded at the Reeves Beaux Arts Studios in New York City on Apr. 28, 1947, conducted by Stravinsky.
  - Igor Stravinsky - Dumbarton Oaks concerto; parts 2 and 3, 1947; MS003.005.106.00014 (Box 106)
  - Igor Stravinsky - Dumbarton Oaks concerto; liner notes, 1947; MS003.005.106.00015 (Box 106)
    Liner notes copied from original album cover.
  - Stravinsky - Symphonie de Psaumes; parts 1 and 2, MS003.005.106.00016 (Box 106)
    Columbia label. Orchestra des Concerts Straram and Alexis Vlassoff Chorus, conducted by Stravinsky. Sung in Latin.
  - Stravinsky - Symphonie de Psaumes; parts 3 and 4, MS003.005.106.00017 (Box 106)
  - Stravinsky - Symphonie de Psaumes; parts 5 and 6, MS003.005.106.00018 (Box 106)
  - Stravinsky - Symphonie de Psaumes; liner notes, MS003.005.106.00019 (Box 106)
    Handwritten liner notes from Porter? Copied from original album cover.
- Political, military, and judicial figures; photographs, prints, and clippings, 1789 -- 1999; MS003.006; 7.2 Linear Feet
  The series contains mostly photographs and prints of political, military, and judicial figures plus a few clippings. Most images are duplicates, in albums, autographed, and many recent ones are dedicated to Porter. We have not determined which portraits or signatures are originals; dates of creation are unclear. Of note are signatures of all American presidents from George Washington to Ronald Reagan as well as John Hancock, Robert Kennedy, and Earl Warren. See also series one for portraits of political figures.
  This series is arranged by political, military/political, and judicial figures.
  - Presidential Administrations [Vol. I], 1789 -- 1825; MS003.006.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Album.
  - [George Washington], ca. 1970's-1980's, 1970 -- 1980; MS003.006.001.00002 (Box 1)
    Clippings
  - Washington's coach, ca. 20th century, 1900 -- 1999; MS003.006.001.00003 (Box 1)
    Print.
  - Presidential Administrations Vol. II, 1825 -- 1845; MS003.006.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Presidential Administrations Vol. III, 1845 -- 1861; MS003.006.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - [Presidential Administrations, ca. mid- 19th century, Vol. IV], MS003.006.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - [Abraham Lincoln], 1970 -- 1980; MS003.006.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - [Presidential Administrations, ca. mid- to late 19th century, Vol. V], MS003.006.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - [Presidential Administrations, ca. late 19th century, Vol. VI], MS003.006.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - [Presidential Administrations, ca. early to mid- 20th century, Vol. VII], MS003.006.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - [Harding Memorial booklet], 1920; MS003.006.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - [Political figures], 1950; MS003.006.002.00005 (Box 2)
    Photographs.
  - [Political figures], 1920 -- 1950; MS003.006.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - [Presidential Administrations, ca. mid- 20th century, Vol. VIII], MS003.006.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - [Campaign materials and political figures], 1940 -- 1980; MS003.006.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - [Presidential Administrations, Vol. IX], 1960 -- 1970; MS003.006.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - [Richard and Patricia Nixon], 1960; MS003.006.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Reagan Administration [Vol. X], 1980; MS003.006.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Governors of Massachusetts 1629-to date, MS003.006.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - United States Senators from Massachusetts 1789-to date, MS003.006.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - U.S. Speakers House of Representatives, 1880 -- 1980; MS003.006.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - World War I Personalities Vol. I, MS003.006.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - World War I Personalities Vol. II, MS003.006.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - World War I Personalities Vol. III, MS003.006.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - [Military/Political figures], 1820 -- 1950; MS003.006.005.00001 (Box 5)
    Photographs [in box].
  - World War I Personalities Vol. IV, MS003.006.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - World War I Personalities Vol. V, MS003.006.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - [Military figures], 1940 -- 1980; MS003.006.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - [Military figures], 1950 -- 1960; MS003.006.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00018 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00019 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00020 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00021 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00022 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00023 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00024 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00025 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00026 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00027 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00028 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00029 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00030 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00031 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00032 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00033 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], ca. 20th century, MS003.006.006.00034 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], ca. 20th century, MS003.006.006.00035 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00036 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00037 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00038 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00039 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00040 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00041 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00042 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00043 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], ca. 20th century, MS003.006.006.00044 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00045 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], ca. 20th century, MS003.006.006.00046 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00047 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00048 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00049 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00050 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00051 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00052 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00053 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00054 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00055 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00056 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00057 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00058 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00059 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00060 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00061 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00062 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00063 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00064 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00065 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00066 (Box 6)
  - [Supreme Court Justice], 1800 -- 1900; MS003.006.006.00067 (Box 6)